A Guide to the William Faulkner Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6271-ag
William Faulkner Collection ca. 1930-1973
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6271-ag
ca. 15 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
This portion of the Massey-Faulkner Collection was transferred from the Rare Books Department on 17 September 1974, having been given to the library some years before.
Item Listing
- Big Woods Uncorrected proofs, 1955; 212 p. on [128] l.
- Faulkner In the University, Class Conferences at the University of Virginia, 1957-1958, edited by Frederick L. Gwynn and Joseph L. Blotner, 1959
  Galley Proofs with typescript additions and extensive marginal ms corrections and notes throughout, 79 l.; Galley Proofs with marginal ms corrections throughout, 78 l.
- Flags in the Dust, edited with an introduction by Douglas Day, 1973
  Galley Proofs stamped "Marked Set" with ms note "Master Set 1/7/73," with marginal ms corrections throughout, 122 l.; Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 122 l.; Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 122 l.; Page proofs stamped "Marked Set" with ms note "Master Set 3/27/73," with marginal ms corrections throughout, [129] l.
- Intruder in the Dust, 1948
  Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 122 l.
- A Lion in the Garden, Interviews with William Faulkner, 1926- 1962, edited by James B. Meriwether and Michael Millgate, 1968
- The Mansion, 1959
  Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 153 l.
- New Orleans Sketches, edited by Carvel Collins, 1967
  Uncorrected Advance Proofs, 63 l. in slipcase.
- Sanctuary, 1930-1931
  Uncorrected Galley Proofs of first version, 1930, 103 l. Available to readers on microfilm only, M-1389; Author's proof, 1931, unbound pre-publication issue with marginal holograph notes throughout, New York, Jonathan Cape edition [2] 380 p. in slipcase.
- The Town, 1956
  Galley Proofs with marginal ms corrections, 119 l.
- " By the People, " a short story appearing in Prize Stories, 1957, selected and edited by Paul Engle
- " Sunday Morning at the Compsons, " a short story appearing in Gallery World's Best Magazine, 1950
  Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 6 l. in slipcase, story appears on leaves 46-51.
- " Mississippi, " an article appearing in Ten Years of Holiday, by the editors of Holiday Magazine, 1956
  Uncorrected Galley Proofs, 223 l., article appears on leaves 134-142.
- The Tragic Mask, by John Lewis Langley, 1963
  Galley Proofs with marginal holograph notes, 87 l.